Olga Pichuzhkina

Python Developer

4 17.10.1998

Tbilisi, Georgia

**** +7 (926) 011-21-13

+995 599 02 56 36



in linkedin.com/in/vyhuholl

github.com/vyhuholl

@ vyhuholl@protonmail.com

∢ olgap981

About me

Python developer and data scientist specializing in NLP. My primary stack is Python, but I also have some experience with Golang.

I am proactive and highly dedicated, a quick learner, and always strive to improve my skills. I also have some experience as a lecturer and a mentor in ML/Python training courses for entry-level specialists.

EXPERIENCE

Python Engineer	Developed a number of tools for speech processing.	⊞	11.2022 – 02.2023 Crowdtesting
Education Mentor	Mentor of the "Data Science" course (module "Mathematics in ML").	⊞	12.2022 – ongoing SkillFactory
Education Mentor	Mentor of the "Python for beginners" course.	⊞	10.2022 – ongoing Netology
Data Scientist	Retrained a model for text generation task, and integrated the new model into company products. Developed a tool for Russian text augmentation.	☆	07.2022 – 09.2022 CYBERBOREA
Python Developer (freelance)	Developed a number of tools for NLP tasks.	#	05.2022 - 06.2022
ML Engineer	Developed a number of audio classification models. Collected, preprocessed, and validated data for models' training.	⊞	01.2021 – 10.2021 IT ForYou

SKILLS

Python	
R	
Golang	
Data Science	•••••
ML	•••••
DL	
NLP	•••••
Algorithms	
Mathematics	
SQL	
Redis	
Flask	
Django	
FastAPI	
pytest	
HTML	
CSS	
Linux	
Bash	
Git	
Docker	

LANGUAGES

English	C1*	
Russian	$C2^*$	
		Native

EDUCATION

Fundamental and Computational Linguistics



Higher School of Economics, Moscow

EXPERIENCE

Teaching assistant	Teaching assistant of the "Programming and Linguistics Data" and "Introduction to Data Analysis" university courses and the "Introduction to Artifical Intelligence" online course.	⊞	09.2019 – 07.2021 Higher School of Economics
Author	Author of education materials (rubrics "Essentials", "Math", and "Python") for the education platform Hyperskill.	⊞	02.2019 – 02.2021 Higher School of Economics